Joseph Pellegrino

Senior Software Engineer

e: joseph.j.pellegrino@gmail.com p: 916.834.3643

OVERVIEW

Driven, self-managed, and resourceful individual with the goal of delivering results. Over my professional career I have worked to build my career through continuous learning in order to maximize corporate business direction. I bring a positive attitude and energy to the workplace and enjoy working with others who value integrity, compassion, enthusiasm, and work ethic.

SKILLS

- Angular 7
- Javascript
- HTML5
- CSS

- ES6
- SQL
- User Experience Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Senior Software Engineer, Centene (August 2018 - Present)

Work within a team to develop applications in Angular 7, Javascript and Java. Lead development of all UI related work including but not limited to a print/file traffic manager, complex print bundle ordering form, and an administrator portal to manage access for all internal employees. These applications consist of over thirty-five components within the three applications and are written in Angular 7 with API's built in Java. Key contributions outside of development work include influencing decisions for best tools and practices for enterprise use and to support and mentor junior developers and other peers as well as a point of contact for business stakeholders to drive initiatives

UI Engineer, Intel (September 2016 - July 2017)

Work with a team to design and develop responsive web applications and data-driven dashboards using Angular 2+. Improve UX/UI on existing applications through user testing, surveys and other UX techniques. Build mockups and prototypes for presentation to stakeholders.

Front-End Web Developer, Aerojet Rocketdyne (April 2014 - September 2016)

Developed informational websites for various business groups to drive awareness and promote culture throughout the enterprise. Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery. Met with stakeholders to identify project goals. Design projects based on requirements and iterate design to match stakeholder vision.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree Program, Digital Media Design

National University, La Jolla, CA